Until recently, there wasn't a special integrated development environment made just for platform developers
like us, but now we've got something awesome to cheer about.
While tools such as Aegaeon help load modulus in IntelliJ or Android Studio, they had their limitations.
Now Google has introduced Android Studio for platform and dedicated crafted for platform developers.
Let's take a closer look at how it helps.
Android studio for platform is a specialized version of the Android Studio IDE.
It is tailor for AOSp platform developers.
It utilizes the song build system as PHP has multi-language support.
SFP allows you to edit C plus, plus, Kotlin and Java programming languages within a single integrated
development environment.
SFP provides Project Setup Wizard, which we will look in a while at.
Assist in configuring your lunch target and platform modules.
Let's download Android Studio for platform.
Search for Android Studio for platform in Google.
Here is the official page from where we can download it.
Download the zip file for Linux.
Okay.
Download is completed to install the deb file.
Open one terminal window type sudo d pick.
G hyphen I path to the d file.
So go to the location where it was installed.
Run studio Dot FX to open Android Studio for platform.
It will open up the standard welcome screen.
Click on Import Project.
In this window we need to select the location of AOSp.
Then the lunch target.
I am selecting the mobile emulator built.
In the module paths.
Add the modules which you wish to work on.
Let's add the frameworks module.
Leave a project name and the location of the project.
Click on finish.
It may take a while to load the module and build it.
The framework module will be opened up with all its dependencies.
Now you can navigate through the project like any other Android to your project.
Java, Kotlin and C plus plus files are supported.
Let's try adding a new module.
Same steps.
Select the project you wish to open.
Finish.
Let's open a new window.
Overall it's nice, but there are still limitations.
Like you cannot see their sources and full build of some individual apps fails.
ET cetera.
Hope it was helpful.
Please try it out and let us know your feedback.
Thank you.